Mss.Rec.166 Mss.Rec.166
American Philosophical Society
Interviews on Cheyenne, Comanche, Kiowa, and Apache military societies
1992-1993
Mss.Rec.166
American Philosophical Society
13.0 Tape(s)
Audio recordings of interviews with Cheyenne, Comanche, Kiowa, and Kiowa Apache consultants regarding military societies, related dances and ceremonial traditions, the participation of Indians veterans in the U.S. military during wars in the 20th century--including Comanche code talkers--and related topics. Also includes recordings of performances by the Comanche Tuhwi Society, Kiowa Black Legs Society, Kiowa Scalp & Victory Dance Songs, Kiowa children's songs, and some Kiowa folklore. Recorded by William C. Meadows in various locations in Oklahoma in 1992 and 1993.
13 sound cassettes (16 hr., 32 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Blackbear, Eugene, Jr.
Bull Coming, Catharine
Bull Coming, Roy Dean, Jr.
Chalepah, Alfred, Sr.
Chalepah, Alfred
Chalepah, Alonzo
Domebo, Harry
Kassanavoid, Forrest
Klinekole, Houston
Meadows, William C.
Tongkeahma, Henrietta
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by William Meadows in 1994 (Acc. 1994-127r). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Related Archival Materials
Extensive notes on taped interviews and related, untaped interviews are available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Cheyenne Indians--Social life and customs; Cheyenne Indians--Societies, etc.; Comanche Indians--Music; Comanche Indians--Social life and customs; Comanche Indians--Societies, etc.; Indian code talkers; Indian veterans; Kiowa Apache dance; Kiowa Apache Indians--Social life and customs; Kiowa Apache Indians--Societies, etc.; Kiowa dance; Kiowa Indians--Music; Kiowa Indians--Social life and customs; Kiowa Indians--Societies, etc.; Secret societies--Great Plains; Sound recordings; World War, 1939-1945--Participation, Indian.
- Audio recordings
  - Cheyenne Military Societies [1 of 2], 1993-04-24; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:40:24; Bull Coming, Catharine; Bull Coming, Roy Dean, Jr.; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Scope and Contents note
    Summary transcript available in the Phillips Fund collection (Mss.497.3.Am4). See Related Resource.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Cheyenne dance; Cheyenne Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Cheyenne Indians--Societies, etc.; Oklahoma; Sun-dance
  - Cheyenne Military Societies [2 of 2], 1993-04-24; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:53; Bull Coming, Catharine; Bull Coming, Roy Dean, Jr.; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Cheyenne Military Societies [1 of 8], 1992-10-09; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:39; Blackbear, Eugene, Jr.; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Cheyenne dance; Cheyenne Indians--Societies, etc.; Norman (Okla.); Sun-dance
  - Cheyenne Military Societies [2 of 8], 1992-10-09; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:54; Blackbear, Eugene, Jr.; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Cheyenne Military Societies [3 of 8], 1992-12-09; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:43; Blackbear, Eugene, Jr.; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Cheyenne dance; Cheyenne Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Cheyenne Indians--Societies, etc.; Norman (Okla.)
  - Cheyenne Military Societies [4 of 8], 1992-12-09; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:36; Blackbear, Eugene, Jr.; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Cheyenne Military Societies [5 of 8], 1992-12-09; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:20; Blackbear, Eugene, Jr.; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Cheyenne Military Societies [6 of 8], 1992-12-10; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:22; Blackbear, Eugene, Jr.; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Cheyenne Military Societies [7 of 8], 1992-12-10; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:36:38; Blackbear, Eugene, Jr.; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Cheyenne Military Societies [8 of 8], 1992-12-10; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:51; Blackbear, Eugene, Jr.; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Comanche Tuhwi Society Music, 1993-07-17; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:37; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Comanche Indians--Music; Comanche Indians--Societies, etc.; Walters (Okla.)
  - Apache Military Societies & Dances [1 of 4], 1993-03-25; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:45:57; Chalepah, Alfred; Chalepah, Alonzo; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Kiowa Apache dance; Kiowa Apache Indians--Societies, etc.; Oklahoma
  - Apache Military Societies & Dances [2 of 4], 1993-03-25; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:34:46; Chalepah, Alfred; Chalepah, Alonzo; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Apache Military Societies & Dances [3 of 4], 1993-03-25; 05-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:23; Chalepah, Alfred; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Apache Military Societies & Dances [4 of 4], 1993; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:12; Chalepah, Alfred; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Song about a little calf, 1993; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:41; Meadows, William C., 1966-; Tongkeahma, Henrietta
    Song introduced in English. Second singer not identified.
    Kiowa Indians--Music; Oklahoma
  - Song about a prairie dog, 1993; 06-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:59; Meadows, William C., 1966-; Tongkeahma, Henrietta
  - Song about a prairie dog looking out of a hole, 1993; 06-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:11; Meadows, William C., 1966-; Tongkeahma, Henrietta
  - Song about a little bird, 1993; 06-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; Meadows, William C., 1966-; Tongkeahma, Henrietta
  - Song about a bullfrog, 1993; 06-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:53; Meadows, William C., 1966-; Tongkeahma, Henrietta
  - Song about a little boy and his grandmother, 1993; 06-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:06; Meadows, William C., 1966-; Tongkeahma, Henrietta
  - Song about an old lady and her pet snake, 1993; 06-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; Meadows, William C., 1966-; Tongkeahma, Henrietta
  - Lullaby, 1993; 06-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:24; Meadows, William C., 1966-; Tongkeahma, Henrietta
    Kiowa Indians--Music; Lullabies, Kiowa; Oklahoma
  - Song to calm down children, 1993; 06-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:34; Meadows, William C., 1966-; Tongkeahma, Henrietta
  - Song about a red worm, 1993; 06-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:14; Meadows, William C., 1966-; Tongkeahma, Henrietta
  - Two songs for a girls' game, 1993; 06-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:10; Meadows, William C., 1966-; Tongkeahma, Henrietta
  - Story about Sendeh, prairie dogs, and coyote, 1993; 06-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:12; Meadows, William C., 1966-; Tongkeahma, Henrietta
    Kiowa Indians--Folklore; Oklahoma
  - Interview with Alfred Chalepah, Sr., 1993; 06-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:48; Chalepah, Alfred; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Kiowa Military Societies [1 of 3], 1993-06-18; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:35:03; Domebo, Harry; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Kiowa dance; Kiowa Indians--Societies, etc.; Oklahoma
  - Kiowa Military Societies [2 of 3], 1993-06-18; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:49:37; Domebo, Harry; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Kiowa Military Societies [3 of 3], 1993-06-18; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:55; Domebo, Harry; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Kiowa Black Legs Society Songs, 1993-10; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:00; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Kiowa dance; Kiowa Indians--Music; Kiowa Indians--Societies, etc.; Oklahoma
  - Apache Military Service & Societies [1 of 2], 1993-06-30; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:47:21; Klinekole, Houston; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Boone (Okla.); Indian veterans; Kiowa Apache Indians--Societies, etc.; Korean War, 1950-1953--Participation, Indian; World War, 1939-1945--Participation, Indian
  - Apache Military Service & Societies [2 of 2], 1993-06-30; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:37; Klinekole, Houston; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Boone (Okla.); Indian veterans; Kiowa Apache Indians--Societies, etc.; Kiowa Apache language; Korean War, 1950-1953--Participation, Indian; World War, 1939-1945--Participation, Indian
  - Comanche Dances & Military Societies, 1993-07-12; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:53; Kassanavoid, Forrest; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Comanche dance; Comanche Indians--Societies, etc.; Comanche language; Indiahoma (Okla.)
  - Comanche Divisions Dances, Veterans, Military Societies, 1993-07-12; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:41; Kassanavoid, Forrest; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Comanche dance; Comanche Indians--Societies, etc.; Indiahoma (Okla.); Indian code talkers; Indian veterans; World War, 1939-1945--Participation, Indian
  - Comanche Military Societies [1 of 2], 1993-07-12; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:02; Kassanavoid, Forrest; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Comanche Military Societies [2 of 2], 1993-08-03; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:35:56; Kassanavoid, Forrest; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Kiowa Scalp & Victory Dance Songs, 1993; 11-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:43; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Apache War Dance Society [1 of 2], 1993-12-02; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:08; Chalepah, Alfred; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Anadarko (Okla.); Kiowa Apache dance; Kiowa Apache Indians--Societies, etc.
  - Apache War Dance Society [2 of 2], 1993-12-02; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:51:42; Chalepah, Alfred; Meadows, William C., 1966-
  - Apache War Dance Society, Women's Dances, Cedaring, Names of Apache Dances, 1993-12-02; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:51:56; Chalepah, Alfred; Meadows, William C., 1966-
    Anadarko (Okla.); Kiowa Apache dance; Kiowa Apache Indians--Societies, etc.; Kiowa Apache language